<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Laments of the Struggling Researcher</title>
    <link>https://thexavier666.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Laments of the Struggling Researcher</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>sumitros@gmail.com (Sumitro Bhaumik)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>sumitros@gmail.com (Sumitro Bhaumik)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2017 Sumitro Bhaumik</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 12:30:31 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thexavier666.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating an actual OpenFlow-enabled Gigabit Switch</title>
      <link>https://thexavier666.github.io/2017/06/20/creating-an-actual-openflow-enabled-gigabit-switch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 12:30:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>sumitros@gmail.com (Sumitro Bhaumik)</author>
      <guid>https://thexavier666.github.io/2017/06/20/creating-an-actual-openflow-enabled-gigabit-switch/</guid>
      <description>Development in SDN can be an issue if you do not have access to proper hardware. Good SDN switches can cost upwards of 2000$ (Rs 1,50,000). An alternative to dedicated switches would be makeshift switches using standard PCs, with a few extra ports. Here is a tutorial showing how to convert a PC into an SDN switch.
Hardware needed to create a OpenFlow switch All of this should be available at a good computer hardware store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Hugo and possible errors</title>
      <link>https://thexavier666.github.io/2017/06/19/using-hugo-and-possible-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 23:23:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>sumitros@gmail.com (Sumitro Bhaumik)</author>
      <guid>https://thexavier666.github.io/2017/06/19/using-hugo-and-possible-errors/</guid>
      <description>Installing Hugo is not a big deal. You just have to download the proper deb file from their site. But using it, is another issue. The main problem that I faced was using the themes. Every theme has a toml configuration file which is in charge of all the web elements (forgive me misusing the terms for I don&amp;rsquo;t web development too well). The problem is that theme makers use different toml files; some are feature-rich and some are barren.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo is nice!</title>
      <link>https://thexavier666.github.io/2017/06/19/hugo-is-nice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 19:41:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>sumitros@gmail.com (Sumitro Bhaumik)</author>
      <guid>https://thexavier666.github.io/2017/06/19/hugo-is-nice/</guid>
      <description>This is my first post in this site (Technically)
Since I am not the sharpest tool in the shed, I needed to try out Hugo for an entire afternoon to make it work properly.
I had some difficulty in understanding how to setup the custom themes. Then I had the brilliant idea of moving the theme.toml file to the Hugo directory and lo, the site was created properly!
This theme that I&amp;rsquo;m using is called Hyde-y, which is extremely clean, Material-designed, and hopefully responsive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who am I?</title>
      <link>https://thexavier666.github.io/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 17:08:46 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>sumitros@gmail.com (Sumitro Bhaumik)</author>
      <guid>https://thexavier666.github.io/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>Hi! This is Sumitro.
I&amp;rsquo;m just a guy who is dipping his feet in web development for the first time
Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m doing a PhD at IIT Kharagpur in Computer Science and Engineering.
You can know more about me in my academic website here
You can contact me by using the icons on the Sidebar.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>